A Register of the Archimandrite Polikarp Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Archimandrite Polikarp Papers
1917-1958
2008C70
Polikarp, Archimandrite (Gorbunov), 1880-1970
1 microfilm reel (0.15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
These papers contain the personal papers of Archimandrite Polikarp (Gorbunov). After the Russian Revolution, Archimandrite Polikarp found himself in Harbin, China, where he was closely associated with Metropolitan Meletii (Zaborovskii), and was assigned as rector of the Annunciation cathedral.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
The entire collection is available on Microfilm
Location of Original Materials
Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Biography
1880 Born, Shingali, Kazanskaia guberniia, Russia
1910 Tonsured monk
1911 Ordained hierodeacon
1914 Ordained hieromonk
1970 Died, Jordanville, NY
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers contain the personal papers of Archimandrite Polikarp (Gorbunov). After the Russian Revolution, Archimandrite Polikarp found himself in Harbin, China, where he was closely associated with Metropolitan Meletii (Zaborovskii), and was assigned as rector of the Annunciation cathedral. After fleeing from Harbin, Archimandrite Polikarp relocated to Hong Kong, and finally emigrated to the U.S.A., where he entered Holy Trinity Monastery in Jordanville, N.Y. The Subject file includes an inventory of ecclesiastical items of the Harbin Annunciation cathedral.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into two series: Biographical file, and Subject file
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the online catalog.
Subjects
Annunciation cathedral, Harbin.; Meletii, Metropolitan of Harbin and Manchuria.
Collection Contents
- Biographical file, 1917-1942. (Box 1)
  Commemoration book, congratulatory addresses, ecclesiastical documents
  - Commemoration book, undated (Folder 1: 1)
  - Congratulatory addresses, 1929-1942 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Ecclesiastical documents, 1917-1920 and undated (Folder 1: 3)
- Subject file, 1938-1958.
  Ecclesiastical certificates, inventory, ukazy, will
  - Annunciation cathedral, Harbin
    - Certificates of ordination, undated (Folder 1: 4)
    - Inventory of ecclesiastical items, 194? (Folder 1: 5)
    - Ukazy, 1939-1958 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Meletii, Metropolitan of Harbin and Manchuria. Last will, 1938 (Folder 1: 7)